American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Native American Languages. 1882-1958 Mss.497.3.B63c
American Philosophical Society
- Nootka (Nuuchahnulth)
  - Nootka lexicon, ca. 1895; AMs, ca.1,500slips.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Nootka words, partly arranged by stems and suffixes, evidently in Albemi dialect.
    Freeman and Smith 2409
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.1, reel 55
  - Nootka tales, 1913-1914; AMs and TMs, part Cy, 1275L.; Sapir, Edward and Hunt, George
    Folkloristic tales written in English by George Hunt, revised and reworked by Edward Sapir. Occasional native forms. Typed documents follow the Hunt MS. Images include pencil and ink sketches of dwelling, sling.
    Freeman and Smith 2405
    Cf. Sapir and Swadesh (1939).
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 25-26
    - Eagle totem, 1914
  - The internal economy of the Nootka word (a semantic study of word structure in a polysynthetic language), 1933; TMs, 149L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Doctoral dissertation presented at Yale University. Published in revised form. c.c. in No. 30 (W2a.11)
    Freeman and Smith 2420
    Printed, with changes in orthography and rearranged, Swadesh (1939) and in Sapir and Swadesh (1939).
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.6, reel 6
  - Nootka dance calls, with musical notations, n.d.; AMs, 3L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Freeman and Smith 2406
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 26
  - Nootka ethnographic texts... ed. by Morris Swadesh, n.d.; TMs part Cy, 1083 l. 8 parts.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Volumes 2 and 3, a sequel to Sapir and Swadesh (1939). These 142 texts have not been published. Phonetic system is that used for Sapir and Swadesh (1939). Translations, made by Swadesh, are generally free. Originals in National Museum of Canada. Copies made by Swadesh, 1947
    Freeman and Smith 2414
    Microfilmed as: Film 372, reel 26-27
  - A list of Nootka suffixes, 1935; TMs Cy, 94L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939, and Morris Swadesh
    Freeman and Smith 2416
    Cf. different list in Sapir and Swadesh (1939):316-334.
  - Nootka phonology and morphology, 1937; TMs, 239L., 2 slips.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Contains discussions of abbreviated name forms, paradigmatic suffixes, variable length stem vowels (with note of E. Sapir), reduplicating suffixes, shortening of variable length vowels, phonology of incremental suffixes, quantitative ablaut, vocative, vocalic contraction.
    Freeman and Smith 2422
  - English-Nootka vocabulary, 1952; TMs, 48L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Alphabetical list, by the English, based on part 3 of Sapir and Swadesh (1939).
    Freeman and Smith 2419
  - Relations between Nootka and Quileute, ca. 1928; TMs with Ms. Additions, 11p.; also Cy 10p.; Andrade, Manuel José, 1885-1941
    Includes ALS note from E. Sapir to Andrade, n.d.
    Freeman and Smith 2408
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown, 1952 and 1954. Printed in edited and abbreviated form, introduced by Morris Swadesh, as Andrade (1953b).
  - Nootka structural and phonetic notes, 1931-1935; AMs and TMs part Cy, ca. 300L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Rough drafts of articles and various materials prepared by Swadesh in connection with his dissertation [No. 2421] and with work done while Swadesh served as assistant to Sapir. Some correspondence between the two, discussing various points. Loose notes on sentences and c.c. of No. 2422
    Freeman and Smith 2424
  - Nootka lexical file, 1930; AMs and TMs, part Cy, ca. 65,000 slips.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Pt. 6 is No. 2402.
    Freeman and Smith 2415
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.6, reel 6-14
  - Nootka ethnographic notes, 1949; AMs and TMs, 44L. 5 notebooks.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Includes some linguistic material in a notebook of vocabulary and miscellaneous items. Deals mainly with composition of groups of persons inhabiting old-fashioned Nootka multi-family houses. Images include pencil sketches, maps of village on Vancouver Island, Alberni.
    Freeman and Smith 2407
  - Material on Nootka aspect, n.d.; AMs and TMs, 375L., 13 slips.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Notes and various revision of article with annotations and comments by Edward Sapir. Explanatory note by author, May, 1953. (Draft of a master's thesis. cf. No. 2424.)
    Freeman and Smith 2421
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 23
  - Miscellaneous Nootka material, n.d.; TMs and AMs, ca. 1600L., 19 notebooks of ca. 100 p. each, 5 notebooks of ca. 200 p. each, and ca. 750 slips.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Includes: ethnographic notes, often with Nootka terms; some drawings by a Nootka; census data. Notebooks are the source of material in the typed notes. Slips are alphabetical lists of Nootka personal and place names. Table of contents available. Images in notebooks, numbers 6, 22, 32-35, 37-38, 51, 64, 77-79, 81-88 include color pencil sketches on photomechanical printed faces of tattoos, masks; crayon drawings of totem figures, canoes, weapons, masks, hunting; black and white illustrations of masks, totems, rattles, utensils, weapons; black and white gelatin silver prints of group and individual portraits.
    Freeman and Smith 4586
    Donor, Sapir family, May 1972
    Drawings.; Gelatin silver prints; Illustrations.; Photomechanical prints; Sketches.
- Northeast
  - Frank Speck annotated maps, 2.0 Map; 2 maps (extra-oversize); Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950
    - Frank Speck Map Labrador Area I, 85.6 x 78.3 cm
      Speck title: "Map of Northeastern United States and Canada Showing Family Hunting Territories and Boundaries of Bands and Tribes as far as the Survey has been carried." Signed, "Frank G Speck Dept. of Anthropology".
      Base map: An unidentified printed map of northeastern U.S. and southeastern Canada. Cropped. No date. [Annotated map was formerly grouped with Northwest Coast material of J.A. Teit.]
    - [Map of hunting territories in Quebec and Labrador.], 91.0 x 83.3 cm
      Annotated map depicting Montagnais-Naskapi, Cree, and Algonquin-Ojibwa linguistic groups of the Labrador peninsula.
      Base map: "Map of Labrador Peninsula. Base map from plats of map of Canada, Department of Interior." No date. Scale 1:2,217,600. [Annotated map was formerly grouped with Northwest Coast material of J.A. Teit.]
- Northwest Coast
  - Excerpts from various historical source materials on the Indians of Vancouver Island and adjacent mainland. With maps, 1790-1915; TMs, 157L., chart, and maps. Photo.; Unidentified
    Extensive excerpts from printed sources relating to Northwest Coast Indians.
    Freeman and Smith 2438
  - List of Northwest Coast material culture objects, 1920; AMs, 600 cards.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Reference numbers to catalogue of unnamed museum. Some names written phonetically and translated
    Freeman and Smith 2430
  - Excerpts from materials in the possession of the Hudson's Bay Company, 1830-1850; TMs, 79L.; Hudson's Bay Co.
    Materials obtained by Franz Boas from the Company in 1939. Includes ethnographic material and white-Indian economic relations. Extracts from: George Blenkinsop, Fort Rupert Journal, 1849-1850; Donald Manson, Journal of a voyage up Nass River, 1832; Fort Simpson, Nass, iournal, 1830-1840 and 1842. Covering letters included
    Freeman and Smith 2437
  - Linguistic reports of the British Association for the Advancement of Science; a general review, ca. 1910; TMs, 11p.; Frachtenberg, Leo Joachim, 1883-1930
    Critical bibliography of BAAS Reports, 1885-1902. Compiled for Franz Boas. Never published
    Freeman and Smith 2451
  - Annotated Maps and Notes to maps of the Pacific Northwest, 1910-1913; AMs, 81L, and 16 commercial maps.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Maps of historic tribal locations and trade routes during the nineteenth century. Notes explain maps. Three letters of Teit to Boas, 1910-1913, referring to Chehalis, Quinault, Klallam, Cowlitz, and Willapa. Tonixa Kutenai, and Kalispel materials.
    Freeman and Smith 2446
    - Map (1). Montana. 1650 to 1850., 53.0 x 35.4 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating territories of [all names as spelled] “Cour d’Alene, Kalispel, Pend d’Oveille, Flathead, Nez Perce, Shoshonis, Kootenay, Blackfoot.” Other tribal regions are denoted on map, without coloration; these include tribal territories within the map area, and neighboring territories. Overprinted by hand with hachures are areas identified as “Former territory of Tunaxe,” “Former territory of Semteuse, “Piece of territory formerly claimed by Pend d’Oveille,” and “possibly also formerly a part of the Semteuse territory.”
      Base map: “The Rand-McNally Vest Pocket Map of Montana Showing All Counties, Cities, Towns, Railways, Lakes, Rivers, etc.” (c) 1906. Scale 30 miles = 1 inch.
    - Map. No. 1. Western States., 71.2 x 53.4 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating with hachures as well as by colors, “Columbia tribes or group,” “Central or Okangon group of tribes,” “Salish proper or Flathead group of tribes,” “Cour d’Alene” [names as written]. Notations on map: “Map showing early positions and approximate boundaries of tribes in portions of British Columbia, Alberta, Montana, Idaho, Washington, Oregon, and Wyoming. On the whole immediately (prior to the introduction of the horse, the North Western movements of Shahaptian, and Shoshonean bands in Washington and Oregon, the southern movements of the Blackfoot tribes, and the western movements of the Siouan tribes.” “Possibly on the whole circa 1700 A.D. for many of the tribes.” Specific tribes denoted [as spelled]: Salishan (comprising Lillovet, Thompson, Shuswap), Athapaskan, Chinookan, Kalapooian, Waiilatpuan, Lutuamian, Shoshonean, Shahaptian, Kitunahan, Algonquian, Siouan.
      Base map: “Rand McNally & Co.’s Commercial Map of the Western States.” (c) 1908. 1910 printing.
    - Map No. (2) showing approximate positions and boundaries of tribes circa 1840-50 (or before any of the tribes went on reserves)., 70.7 x 53.8 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating tribal regions in southern Alberta, southern British Columbia, Washington, Oregon, Idaho, western Montana, and western Wyoming.
      Base map: “Rand-McNally Commercial Map of the Western States.” (c) 1915. Scale approx. 60 miles = 1 inch.
    - Map (3) showing northern boundaries of the Kalispels, 53.9 x 35.6 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating tribal regions. Colors delineate [as spelled] Pend d’Oveille, Blackfoot, Stony, Lake, Kootenay, Kalispel, Shuswap, Colville.
      Base map: “Rand, McNally & Co.’s Indexed Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of British Columbia....” 1909.
    - Map (3) showing present or late and also former distributions of northern tribes., 69.0 x 53.6 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating distribution of [as spelled] Salishan, Kitunahan, Athapascan family, Algonquian family, Shoshonean, Siouan. Trade routes delineated in red. Annotated map area encompasses Alberta and Saskatchewan, plus western Manitoba, southernmost North West Territories/Yukon, and northern portions of Montana, Idaho, and Washington.
      Base map: “Rand-McNally New Pocket Map of Western Canada Showing Provinces of Alberta and Saskatchewan.” (c) 1906. Scale 60 miles = 1 inch.
    - Map (4) Eastern Washington--Approximate Boundaries Interior Salish tribes about 1825 to 1855., 71.3 x 53.3 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating distribution of [as spelled] Northern group (Thompson), Central or Okanagon group (Okanagon, Lake, Colville, Sans Poil), Eastern or Flathead group (Kalispel, Spokane), Columbia, Coeur d’Alene, Sahaptin tribes, Cayuse about 1850, Cayuse claimed by some about 1860 or earlier to be old boundaries of Cayuse, Kootenay, territory claimed by some Spokane, and approx. boundaries of Spokane divisions. Annotated portions of map also include westernmost Idaho and southernmost British Columbia.
      Base map: “Rand McNally & Co.’s Indexed County and Township Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of Washington...." (c) 1910. Scale 15 miles = 1 inch.
    - Map (4). Showing approximately some of the chief trade routes and trading places, 71.0 x 53.0 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating routes in red, and point locations keyed by number (key not present on map). Annotated areas of map include southernmost British Columbia, southernmost Alberta, Washington, Oregon, California, Idaho, western and central Montana, western and central Wyoming, northwestern Colorado, northeastern Utah.
      Base map: “Rand McNally & Co’s Commercial Map of the Western States.” (c) 1908, 1910 printing.
    - Map (5). Distribution of tribes according to earliest traditions (so far as collected up to date)., 63.0 x 46.5 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating distributions of numerous tribes (though not specially color-coded by tribe). Annotated portion of map includes northernmost Oregon, westernmost Idaho, and southernmost British Columbia. Also noted with title on map: "Boundaries between the tribes are undefined in all the traditions."
      Base map: "Cram’s Indexed County Map and Shipper’s Guide of Washington." Geo. F. Cram, Chicago. No date.
    - Map (6) Washington. Distribution of tribes (languages). 1797., 63.4 x 46.6 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map delineating regions of tribal languages. Also delineated on map is "Approximate northern limits of Snake war parties. see map (8)." [On map, the map number was originally given as Map (7), and the title had originally given the date "about 1790 (and earlier)"; but these were crossed out and the cited data were substituted.]
      Base map: “Cram’s Indexed County Map and Shipper’s Guide of Washington.” Geo. F. Cram, Chicago. No date.
    - Western Washington Map (7). Distribution of Tribes (, 70.0 x 54.0 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map depicting the tribal and linguistic regions of numerous tribes. [On the map, the map number was originally given as Map (3), but was crossed out.]
      Base map: “Rand, McNally & Co.’s Indexed County and Township Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of Washington...." 1909.
    - Map (8) Earliest traditional homes of tribes in Oregon., 71.0 x 53.9 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map depicting tribal home areas generally. Noted on map: "Boundaries between tribes are not defined in the traditions."
      Base map: "Rand McNally & Co.’s Indexed County and Railroad Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of Oregon...." 1910.
    - Map showing as near as possible Location of the Shuswap Tribe and Divisions, with approximate Boundaries of neighboring Tribes., 63.0 x 53.5 cm
      Annotation by Teit: "This map shows the boundaries of the Shuswap, Thompson, Nicola Tinne & Okanagon more correctly than the one I sent with first report on the Thompson Indians part IV vol II." Map also signed "JAT".
      Base map: "Map of the Province of British Columbia. Compiled and drawn by Edward Mohun, C.E., by direction of the Honorable W. Smythe, Chief Commissioner of Lands and Works, Victoria, B.C. 1884." Engraved and printed, J. Bartholomew, Edinburgh. Dawson Brothers, Montreal.
    - [Map of Vancouver Island area with enumerated points.], 92.6 x 62.8 cm
      Map of Vancouver Island and adjacent coasts across which are inscribed many enumerated points, without key on map. One annotation reads, "cairns says Newcoupe," which points to the southern extremity of Valdes Island.
      Base map: "Geological Map of the Northern Part of Vancouver Island and Adjacent Coasts. By George M. Dawson, D.S., F.G.S.etc. (First Edition.) 1887." Geological and Natural History Survey of Canada. Scale 1:506,880.
    - Map (2) showing territory of the Coeur d’Alene, and parts of territories of surrounding tribes., 53.9 x 35.4 cm
      Hand-colored and annotated map of Idaho, depicting the territories of numerous tribes.
      Base map: "Rand, McNally & Co.’s Indexed County and Township Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of Idaho...." 1909.
    - Map showing approximate older boundaries of the Kootenay tribes, and approximate territories of adjoining Salish and other tribe
      Hand-colored and annotated map, signed "JATeit. 1913." Title is further annotated: "from Salish (various tribes) and Kootenay information".
      Base map: “Rand McNally & Co.’s Commercial Map of the Western States.” 1909.
    - [Map of Oregon coastal tribal territories.], 70.6 x 53.4 cm
      Map without title outlining a region of coastal Oregon partly delineated by today's Kalapuya. This region is not labeled but is subdivided into seven enumerated subdistricts, also without other labeling. Bounding this region are adjacent tribal territories labelled (as spelled): Molala, Yakonan, Siuslawan, and Coosan. Segregated territories also labelled on map are Takelman (coastal) and Cayuse (interior, extending into southern Washington). No other annotations are provided on this map.
      Base map: "Rand, McNally & Co.’s Indexed County and Railroad Pocket Map and Shippers’ Guide of Oregon...."
  - Linguistic map of the southern part of Hecate Strait area, British Columbia, Canada, after 1918; Maps, 2 items; United States. Navy Hydrographic Office
    Portion of printed map, U.S. Navy Hydrographic Office, ed., 26 May 1918, with Ms. linguistic data superimposed. Ms. map of same area with similar linguistic data, but smaller in scale.
    Freeman and Smith 2455
- Ntlakyapmuk
  - Salish ethnographic materials, 1898-1910; TMs and AMs, 152L.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Formal paper on attitude of Thompson River Indians toward missionaries; chaps. I and II of addenda to Teit's Traditions of the Thompson River Indians. Notes culled from Teit letters on houses, travel, transportation, canoes, baby carriers, subsistence, stone implements, distribution of tribes, historical notes, and warfare, 1908-1910. Includes 13 complete letters, Teit to Franz Boas, 1906-1916, on Lillooet, Shuswap, Thompson, Flat head, and Pend'Oreille, discussing botany, religion, myths, dances, warfare, trade routes, basketry, blankets, quill work
    Freeman and Smith 2484
    Cf. Teit (1898); No. 3205 and No. 2446.
  - Plant names of Thompson Indians, 1896-1918; AMs and TMs, 2 notebooks. 218L. 1 map.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Latin, English, and Ntlakyapamuk names for plants, with Indian medicinal uses indicated. Ethnobotanical data; lists of plant specimens. 10 letters to James A. Teit from Edward Sapir, James Fletcher, and John Davidson, in regard to botanical specimens.
    Freeman and Smith 2483
  - Thompson River word list, 1914; AMs, 2L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    31 items.
    Freeman and Smith 2491
  - Field notes or Thompson and neighboring Salish languages, 1904; AMs, 18 notebooks.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    12 notebooks of vocabulary arranged ir ethnographic categories. 6 notebooks of eth nographic field notes with drawings, etc Contains also Shuswap, Okanagon, Coeur d'Alene, Spokane materials. Images include pencil sketches of portraits, canoes, papoose, decorative patterns.
    Freeman and Smith 2492
  - Field notes or Thompson songs and language, 1897; AMs, 1 notebook.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Includes 6p. of Chilcotin words.
    Freeman and Smith 2493
  - Ntlakyapamuk relationship terms and terms applied to persons, 1905; AMs, 39p, and 1 slip; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Vocabulary, kinship terms and ,notes.
    Freeman and Smith 2494
    Cf. No. 30(S1b.2).
  - English-Thompson lexicon, 1890; AMs, ca. 430 slips.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Lexical file.
    Freeman and Smith 2486
  - Thompson notes, 1910; AMs, 2L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Freeman and Smith 2488
  - Suffixes in Thompson, with variants in other Salish languages, ca. 1910; TMs with Ms. additions, 14L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    229 items with index. Basic list is dently Thompson and perhaps Kalispel. Chehalis and Coeur d'Alene written in.
    Freeman and Smith 2487
  - Thompson materials, ca.1910; AMs, 2 notebooks. 181p. 15 slips.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Lexical lists; texts; miscellaneous materials, primarily Thompson. Images include ink and pencil sketches of clothing, hieroglyphics.
    Freeman and Smith 2495
  - Thompson River Indians: ethnology, ca.1910; AMs, 19p.; Unidentified
    1p. contents; sketch of subject matter. Ethnographic notes, data, questions.
    Freeman and Smith 2485
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown, Dec. 1954.
  - Manual N'Tla-Ka-Pa-Moh containing catechism, prayers in the Thompson language, to which is added a short vocabulary, and a fe, 1885; Pr. Ms, 77p.; Unidentified
    Cover title: Manual N'tla-kap-moh or of the Thompson language. A few MS. notes in ink (of J. A. Teit?).
    Freeman and Smith 2490
- Ojibwa
  - Shawnee, Kickapoo, Ojibwa, Sauk-and-Fox materials, 1951-1952; TMs, part Cy, with AMs additions, 235L.; Pierce, Joe E.
    Contains discussion of dialect and language relationships, translations of texts, tests, and degree of linguistic relationships. Prepared in part as a Master's thesis, Indiana University.
    Freeman and Smith 2544
    Cf. No. 2543.
  - Chippewa field notes, 1938; AMs, 18L.; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Texts and vocabulary items.
    Freeman and Smith 2546
- Okanagon
  - Okanagan materials, ca. 1900; AMs, 22L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Vocabulary and texts with interlinear translation. Some corresponding Kalispel forms added in red ink
    Freeman and Smith 2550
  - Vocabulary in Okanagon and related dialects, 1908; AMs, 42p.; Teit, James Alexander, 1864-1922
    Besides Okanagon proper, includes forms from Nkaus, Sans Poil, Colville, and Lake dialects, with some parallel forms in Kalispel and Columbia.
    Freeman and Smith 2552
  - Okanagon nurneral forms, 1913; AMs, 1L.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939
    Numerals 1-10 for man, house, canoe, etc.
    Freeman and Smith 2551
  - Okanogon ethnographic notes, 1930; AMs and TMs, part Cy, 250L.; 40 slips and 1 map.; Commons, Rachel
    Field notes. 35 word lists; one ethnographic map; table of contents; outline sketch of Okanagon life; section of text.
    Freeman and Smith 2549
    Donor, Norman A. McQuown, 1955.
- Omaha
  - Omaha (Ponca) and Teton comparative word list, AMs, 4L.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    100 forms.
    Freeman and Smith 2555
  - Omaha (Ponca) lexicon, ca. 1930; AMs, ca. 1,600 cards and slips.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942, et al.
    Items with English equivalents only partially organized; others disorganized. Apparently based on Francis La Flesche and other manuscript sources
    Freeman and Smith 2556
    Microfilmed as: Film 372.7, reel 27-28
  - Omaha grammatical notes, 1928?; AMs, 47L.; La Flesche, Francis
    Notes; vocabulary list either of variant dialect or earlier transcriber
    Freeman and Smith 2559
  - Omaha folkloristic texts, 1928; TMs, 93L.; La Flesche, Francis
    Six texts with literal and free translations; terms of relationship among the Omahas. Covering letters from the author to Boas, May 21 and 26, June 1, 6, and 22, 1928.
    Freeman and Smith 2558
- Oneida
  - Oneida text; verified and corrected by Marius Barbeau, 1950 (1909); AMs, 2p. Photo.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Text in Boas (1909b):455-456 verified by Barbeau working with John Alexander Ninham, a Munsie Reserve Oneida residing at Grand River.
    Freeman and Smith 2568
  - Oneida dialect.., 1950; AMs Cy, 60p.; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969
    Verbal paradigms, parts of the body, natural obiects, etc. Includes check of vocabularies found appended to Jacques Cartier's account of his first and second voyages. Biography of informant, John Alexander Ninham, an Oneida of Munsie Reserve residing at Grand River Reserve
    Freeman and Smith 2567
- Osage
  - Osage materials, 1951; AMs and TMs, part Cy, 158 l.; Wolff, Hans
    Osage field notes; utterances and vocabulary, phonetically transcribed; Osage I: Phonemes and historical phonology. Includes dictated text.
    Freeman and Smith 2612
    Printed (Osage I only), Wolff (1952).
- Otomi